Guide to the Steve Nelson Papers ALBA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Spanish Civil War
  - Subject Files: Political Commissar Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subject Files: Schedule of Speaking Tour, Dec 1937-Jan 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Subject Files: Sheet Music (photocopy of German ballad), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - "A", 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Amery, Alfred, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "B", 1967-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bailey, Bill, undated, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barrett, James, undated, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barrett, James, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Baxandall, Rosalyn, undated, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Belfrage, Cedric, undated, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bender, Ed, undated, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Berch, Victor, 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bertolini, Ethel Shapiro, 1952, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1952-1955, 1974-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Blum, Rudy, undated, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bowie, John W., undated, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bowie, John W., 1970-1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "C", 1960-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Cattonar, Nell Amter, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cohen, Milt, undated, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Collier, Frank, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Colodny, Robert, undated, 1952-1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Colow, Maury, undated, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Crome, Len, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "D", 1969-1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Davis, Peggy, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Davis, Benjamin J., Jr., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Dent, Wally, undated, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Deutsch, Julius, 1975-1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "E", 1952-1990 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Entwistle, Tom, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "F", 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Fast, Howard, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Fishman, Moe, undated, 1953-1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, undated, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "G", 1971-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gaerity, Mary, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Geiser, Carl, 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Glenn, Elinor & Hank, undated, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gordon, Mac, 1976-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gornick, Vivian, 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Groden, Daniel, undated, 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Goldring, Benjamin, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "H", 1967-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hardy, Frank, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Harriman, Manny, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Henrikson, Alan K., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hetzel, Frederick, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hill, Preston, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hunter, Oscar, undated, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hutchins, Evelyn, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hyndman, Katherine, undated, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "I", 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Iceland, Ben, undated, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - International Brigade Association, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Isserman, Maurice, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "J", 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jardas, Edo, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "K", 1966-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Kawanari, Yo, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Keller, Fred, undated, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Kinzer, Stephen, undated, 1975-1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "L", 1961-1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lamb, Leonard & Constance, undated, 1975-1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Lamont, Corliss, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Landis, Arthur, undated, 1952-1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Leric, Danilo, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Levine, Abby, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Levine, Rob, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lloyd, Tom, undated, 1952-1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lowenfels, Walter, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "M", 1966-1991 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Margolis, Mac, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Martin, Fredericka, undated, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Martin, Fredericka, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Martin, Fredericka, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Mates, Dave, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Meeropol, Michael, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Merriman, Marion (Wachtel), 1975-1987 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Minor, Robert & Lydia, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Mitford, Jessica, 1972-1983 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Mostel, Zero, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "N", 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Niihara, Shoji, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - North, Joseph, 1952-[1955] (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Nusser, Charles, undated, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "O", 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Osheroff, Abe, undated, 1974-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ost, Milton, undated, 1974-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "P", 1970-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Prago, Albert, undated, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Q", 1975-1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "R", 1969-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rauschwald, Mark, 1952, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Reed, Bob, undated, 1978-1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Reynolds, Bertha Capon, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Richmond, Al, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Rosenstein, Herman "Gabby" and Mildred, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Ross, Adolph, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ross, Carl, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ruck, Robert, undated, 1971-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "S", 1967-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Seldes, George, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Shifrin, Roy, undated, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sillen, Samuel, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Sills, Sam, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Smith, Randall "Pete", undated, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Smorodin, Abe, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Spencer, Harold, undated, 1952-1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Stamm, Morris and Eleanor, undated, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Steck, Robert, undated, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Stein, Lou, 1977-1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Sterling, Dorothy, 1975-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Stone, I. F., 1954, 1970-1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Susman, William (Bill), 1972-1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "T", 1972-1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Taylor, Robert, 1975-1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Tisa, John, 1971-1983 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Toro, Carlos, undated, 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "U", 1978 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "V", undated, 1967-1982 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Vidali, Vittorio, 1953, 1955, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - "W", 1969-1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Wallach, Hyman, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Watson, William B., 1969-1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Watt, George, 1953-1954, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Weissman, Irving, undated, 1978-1990 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Weisman, Robert, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Wellman, Saul, 1966-1990 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Wilson, H. Hubert, 1968-1976 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Wolff, Milton, 1953, 1970-1990 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Y", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Yates, James, 1952, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "Z", 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Zinn, Howard, 1973-1985 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Unidentified, 1968-1991 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Series III: Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA): Incorporation and Development, 1974-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ALBA: Board Minutes, Financial Reports, Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - African-Americans: Participation in the Spanish Civil War, 1979-1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Award, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary: 30th Celebration, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary: 35th Celebration, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Anniversary: 39th Celebration, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Anniversary: 40th Celebration, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Anniversary: 40th: Trip to Florence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Anniversary: 41st Celebration, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Anniversary: 42nd Celebration, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Anniversary: 43rd-45th Celebrations, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Anniversary: 46th Celebration, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Anniversary: 47th Celebration, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Anniversary: 50th Celebration, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Anniversary: 51st-53rd Celebrations, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Anniversary: 54th Celebration, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Awards and Honors, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Bailey, Bill: Manuscript on U.S. Volunteers, ca.1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Bessie, Alvah: Anthology Manuscript & Prospectus, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Burton, Herbert: "Jews in the International Brigade" (typescript), ca.1937 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - China: Trip, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, ca.1938 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Daily World Dispute: Frankfeld Letter, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dallet, Joseph, Jr.: Memorial Award, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Dorland, Norman: Spanish Civil War memoirs, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Elections, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Elections, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Elections, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Elections, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Feldman, Harold C.: Bequest, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Financial, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Financial, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Financial, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Geiser, Carl: "Prisoners of the Good Fight": Promotional material, undated, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - "Good Fight": Comments and Critiques by George Watt, Steve Nelson and Morris Stamm, Undated; 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - "Good Fight": Proposal, Correspondence, Leaflets and Clippings, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Government Proclamations and Resolutions Honoring the Veterans, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Grant, Walter: "On Being a Minister's Son" (Tribute by Robert Steck), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Grenada: Protest against Invasion, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Historical Commission: Projects and Proposals, undated, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Landis, Arthur, undated, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Landis, Arthur: "United States of America and the Cause of the Spanish Republic, 1936-1939", undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Law, Oliver: Death, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Martin, Fredericka, undated, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Medical Personnel in Spain: Research, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Meetings: New York Post, undated, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Memorials, 1970-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Merriman, Robert Hall: Memorial Award, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Missing Veterans: Adolph Ross Research, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - National Board, 1957, 1969, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - National Conference, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - National Conference, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - National Conference, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - National Conference, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - National Conference, ca.1980 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Nelson, Steve: Birthday Tribute: Greetings, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Nelson, Steve: Birthday Tribute: Contributions, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Nelson, Steve: Birthday Tribute: Publicity, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Nelson, Steve: Birthday Tribute: Request for Sponsors, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Nelson, Steve: Birthday Tribute: Speeches, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Nelson, Steve: Imprisonment, Trial and Appeal, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Nicaragua: Ambulance Fund, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Nicaragua: Opposition to US Policy, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Orwell, George: Material Prepared for the Speakers Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Prisoner Historical Committee, undated, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Resolutions, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Rice, Charles O., 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Sender, Andrea (Sister Benedicta): VALB Anniversary Address, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Spanish Civil War: Clippings, 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Spain: Barcelona Monument, 1977-1988 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Spain: Basque Activists: Montserrat Assembly, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Spain: Madrid Pact, New York Times Protest Ad, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Spain: Trip, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Spain: Trip, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Spain: Trip, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Spain: Trip: International Brigade Reception, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Spain: Volunteers Return: Charles Nusser essay; clippings, 1977, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Spain: Women Prisoners, undated, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Spain and Vietnam: Robert Colodny Speech, ca.1975 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Speakers' Bureau, undated, 1972-1988 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Steinem, Gloria, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Testimonials and Receptions, undated, 1975-1989 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Veterans' Lists, 1981-1991 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Veterans Recognition Campaign, 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Veterans Rights Committee, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - White, David McKelvy: VALB Dues Card, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Wolff, Milton, undated, 1970-1990 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Series IV: Trials and Imprisonment
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 1-121, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 122-496, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 497-747, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 748-908, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 910-1163, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 1431-1768, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 1769-2042, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 2043-2251, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript pp. 2252-2714, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript, Legal Counsel, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript, Summary, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Transcript with notes, Closing Remarks, Dec 1951-Jan 1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Sentencing, Jul 1952- (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Outline & Notes, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: (Appeal), Folder 1, Mar 1953- (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: (Appeal), Folder 2, Mar 1953- (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania vs. Steve Nelson: Petition for Appeal, Draft and Notes, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - United States vs. Steve Nelson, et al.: Indictment, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - United States vs. Steve Nelson, et al.: Opening Statement: William Albertson, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - United States vs. Steve Nelson, et al.: Opening Statement: Steve Nelson, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - United States vs. Steve Nelson, et al.: Opening Statement: Notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - United States vs. Steve Nelson, et al.: Notes, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Transcript of Record: Supreme Court of the United States, October term, 1955, No. 10, Vol. 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Transcript of Record: Supreme Court of the United States, October term, 1955, No. 10, Vol. 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Civil Rights Congress, undated, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Rabinowitz, Victor, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Court Records & Notes, 1951-1954 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Public Appeals & Campaigns, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Release on Bail: Public Statement, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Series V: Writings
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Bound Typescript, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Interview Transcripts & Question Sets, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Interview Transcripts: Pennsylvania Anthracite Mines, ca.1977 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Notes & Comments, ca.1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Notes & Comments: 1937 Arrest in France, ca.1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Promotion & Sales, undated, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Promotion & Sales: Brochure, undated, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Reviews, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Typescripts: Folder 1, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Typescripts: Folder 2, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Steve Nelson: American Radical: Publication Agreement, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Thirteenth Juror: Publication & Promotion, ca.1955-1956 ? (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Thirteenth Juror: Typescript, ca.1955 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Thirteenth Juror: Reviews, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Volunteers: Excerpt in German-published in Aufbau, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Volunteers: Notes and Comments, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Volunteers: Photocopy with Edits, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Volunteers: Publication and Promotion, undated, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Volunteers: Typescripts: Folder 1, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Volunteers: Typescripts: Folder 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Volunteers: Typescripts: Folder 3, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Article: New York Times, "Lincoln Brigade Recalled", 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Article: The Worker, "Upholds Duty to Criticize Fraternal Parties" (Report on Soviet Party's 20th Congress), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Essay: Claude Bowers' My Mission to Spain, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Essay: "Leaving the Party", ca.1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Review: Cecil Eby, Between the Bullet and the Lie, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Review: Cecil Eby, Between the Bullet and the Lie: Draft & Notes, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, undated, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Writings: Drafts and Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Writings: Drafts and Notes: Spanish Civil War, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Subject Files
  - Berry, Abner: Fundraising Drive, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bolloten, Burnett, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Brandt, Joe: "USA Racism: The Stink of the Slave Market", undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Bridges, Harry, undated, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Brunete, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Butler, Smedley: Articles & Biographical Materials, undated, 1935, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Canadian Conference for the Amnesty & Freedom of Spain, 1972 (?) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - City College Volunteers-in-Spain Memorial Scholarship, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: General, undated, 1977-1985 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Colow, Maury: Comments on George Orwell, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Communism: Articles & Essays, 1973 (?) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Conference Participation: Mid-Atlantic Radical Historians' Organization (MARHO), 1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Conference Participation: Programs & Notes, 1981-1988 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Croatia & Yugoslavia, 1972-1975 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Cush, Pat: Biographical Information, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Cvetic, Matt, 1980, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Dennis, Peggy: Unpublished Response to Maurice Isserman on American Communism, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Dolsen, James: Sedition Trial, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - El Salvador, ca.1983 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Fast, Howard: Poem dedicated to Steve Nelson, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - FBI Raids: Detroit, 1940, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - FBI: William Sullivan, The Bureau: My Thirty Years in Hoover's FBI: Excerpt, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley: "The Scar on the Face of Steve Nelson" (Poem), Signed Typescript, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 1, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 2, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 3, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 4, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 5, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 6, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 7, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 8, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 9, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 10, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI Files: Folder 11, ca.1945-1955 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Fund for New Priorities in America, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - German Democratic Republic (DDR): Citation (in honor of the battle against fascism), 1965 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - German Democratic Republic (DDR): Commemorative Stamps Honoring German Anti-Fascists, ca.1970 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Gordon, Max: "Sectarianism and the New American Movement's Electoral Tactics", 1979 (?) (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Granich, Max & Grace: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) documents, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Greer, Edward & John McDermott: "The Road Not Taken", undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Gurney, Jason: Libelous Statements in Crusade in Spain, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Healey, Dorothy: Expulsion from the Communist Party, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - International Brigade: Anniversaries, 1971-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - International Brigade: Book Proposal Conference, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - International Brigade: Canada, 1968-1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - International Brigade: England, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - International Brigade: Germany, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - International Brigade: Ireland, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - International Brigade: Israel, undated, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - International Brigade: Jewish Participation, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - International Brigade: Mexico, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - International Brigade: Netherlands, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - International Brigade: Poland: Dombrowski Brigade, 1971-1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)